

Mário Patrão Software Engineer

PROFILE

Hi, I'm Mário. A Portuguese software engineer living in London for the past 11 years. As a software engineer with 14 years of experience I am now looking to embrace a new challenge that will allow me to grasp new technologies, augment my know-how and work with different "mind-sets".

SKILLS

CONTACT

mariopatrao@gmail.com +44 (0) 7999061551 Flat 5 Hexham Lodge 10-12 Mildmay Park N1 4PG, London

WORK EXPERIENCE

DEVELOPMENT TEAM LEAD @ Wealth Dynamix

March 2018 - To date

I started at WDX as a senior front-end developer working with Angular to help the product team upgrade the core product.

After being promoted to a lead role I started to manage teams for clients like Rothschild and Charles Stanley where I engaged closely with stakeholders and business analysis to translate the different business requirements into the best possible solutions.

In the delivery of these projects, I am using the following tech stack:

- Add and refactor WDX WEB API using C# and .NET WEB API 2;
- Work within the clients' Microsoft CRM Dynamics solutions;
- Create new and expand current components using Angular and JSON;

Additionally, to this role, I am also part of the senior development team. My responsibilities within this group include:

- Working with senior and other lead developers in upgrading our core product, this includes updates to Angular version, updates to our testing solution and test new frameworks to improve several core functionalities;
- Having part ownership of the technical authority group. This means
 managing meetings with around 20 lead and senior developers of all the
 different client projects and help them implement and deliver the new
 core features projected by the design authority group;
- Reporting directly to the Head of Development and the Operations
 Director, I manage three direct reports comprised of mid-level and senior
 developers. This includes having regular 1-2-1 meetings, setting
 performance and development objectives, reviewing their performance
 and supporting them in achieving their goals;
- Mentoring junior developers as part of the WDX Buddy Program;
- Prepare and present companywide KT (knowledge transfer) sessions.
 These sessions can be technical (Angular and C#), or sharing know-hows/best practices/demos for new functionalities added to our core product.

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER @ CTN Group

December 2014 - December 2017

At CTN I was responsible for all aspects of the delivery of our clients' digital projects. This includes:

- Back-end coding (mainly C#);
- Front-end coding of our client facing websites (Razor, CSS, JavaScript, iQuery, Bootstrap);
- Implementation of webcasting platforms provisioned for the delivery of CTN's client's webcasting services;
- Development of internal tools, from scoping through to delivery of the final product;
- Maintain CTN digital infrastructure;
- Working with brand consultants following a company rebrand to create a new vibrant website which can be viewed at https://embolden.agency/;

I have worked with large blue-chip clients including M&S, Unilever, GlaxoSmithKline, RSA, GM&T among many others. On most occasions I was the direct contact for the client and worked with them from conception and execution to final delivery.

WORK EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPER @ ELEMENT 3 SOFTWARE

May 2012 - December 2014

At Element 3 I worked on different web solutions for housing developers to track end to end sales opportunities. I was also part of the team that developed a new web-based document manager named FileHound. All these projects were written to be responsive and fast to convince large organizations to move their workflow into modern web-based platforms.

WEB DEVELOPER @ PLANETA VIRTUAL

June 2009 - March 2012

Planeta Virtual is a software house specialized in web solutions. Its main product is a web portal that is responsible for the human resources, accounting and CRM implemented in several companies. I worked on multiple projects throughout the whole development cycle.

EDUCATION

INFORMATICS ENGINEERING @ FACULTY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY OF THE UNIVERSITY FERNANDO PESSOA OF PORTO

September 2002 – January 2009

COMPUTER SYSTEM ENGINEERING @ THE ACADEMY OF HUMANITIES AND ECONOMICS IN LODZ

September 2006 – July 2007